Guide to the President's Office General Subject and Correspondence Files 1910-1974
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
President's Office General Subject and Correspondence Files
1910-1974
1950-1969
Oregon State University. Office of the President
RG 013 - SG 11
2.70 cubic feet 180 microfilm boxes
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The President's Office General Subject and Correspondence Files consist of microfilmed records documenting the administration and functioning of Oregon State University -- primarily during the 1950s and 1960s.
Historical Note:
Since its designation as a land-grant institution of higher learning in 1868, Oregon State University has had 21 presidents, including 6 acting presidents. They have been William A. Finley, 1865-1872 (Finley was appointed president of the university's predecessor institution, Corvallis Academy, in 1865); Joseph Emery, acting, 1872; Benjamin L. Arnold, 1872-1892; John D. Letcher, acting, 1892; John M. Bloss, 1892-1896; H. B. Miller, 1896-1897; Thomas M. Gatch, 1897-1907; William Jasper Kerr, 1907- 1932; George W. Peavy, acting, 1932-1934, president, 1934-1940; Frank L. Ballard, 1940-1941; Francois A. Gilfillan, acting, 1941- 1942; August L. Strand, 1942-1961; James H. Jensen, 1961-1969; Roy A. Young, acting, 1969-1970; Robert W. MacVicar, 1970-1984; John V. Byrne, 1984-1995; and Paul G. Risser, 1996-2002; Timothy P. White, 2002-2003 (acting); Edward John Ray, 2003-2020; F. King Alexander, 2020-2021; Rebecca L. Johnson, 2021-2022 (acting).
The president is the chief executive officer of the university. From 1868 to 1929 the president reported to the college's Board of Trustees/Regents. Since the creation of the Oregon University System (formerly the Oregon State System of Higher Education) in 1929, the president has reported to the System's chancellor.
Ballard, Frank L. (Frank Llewellyn), 1891-1971; Gilfillan, F. A. (Francois Archibald), 1893-1983; Jensen, James H.; Kerr, William Jasper, 1863-1947; MacVicar, Robert William, 1918-; Oregon State Agricultural College. Office of the President; Oregon State College. Office of the President; Peavy, George Wilcox, 1869-1951; Strand, A. L. (August Leroy), 1894-; Young, Roy A. (Roy Alton), 1921-2013
Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges; KOAC (Radio station: Corvallis, Or.); National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Northwest Association of Secondary and Higher Schools; Oregon Agricultural College; Oregon State Agricultural College; Oregon State Agricultural College--Administration.; Oregon State Board of Higher Education; Oregon State College; Oregon State College--Administration.; Oregon State System of Higher Education; Oregon State University; Oregon State University--Administration.; Oregon State University--Students.; Oregon University System
Microfilms
Corvallis (Or.)
Agriculture; Colleges and Universities; Military; Science; Sports and Recreation; Student Life; Oregon; Corvallis
These materials were transferred to the University Archives in the 1960s and 1970s and microfilmed by the Archives.
Collection is open for research.
SCARC's holdings include myriad collections documenting the work of past OSU presidents and the President's Office as an entity, in a wide variety of formats.
Photographs of OSU presidents are available in the Presidents of Oregon State University Photographic Collection (P 001) and the President's Office Photographs (P 092) as well as many other photographic groups. Moving images of the presidents are available in the President's Office Motion Picture Film and Videotapes (FV 092). SCARC's manuscripts collections include the personal papers of several OSU Presidents; these include the William A. Finley Scrapbook (MSS FinleyWA), John McKnight Bloss Collection (MSS Bloss), F. A. Gilfillan Papers (MSS Gilfillan), George W. Peavy Papers (MSS Peavy), Roy A. Young Papers (MSS YoungRA), the Robert W. MacVicar Papers (MSS MacVicar), and the Paul G. Risser Papers (MSS Risser). The largest extant group of William Jasper Kerr's papers can be found in the Edwin T. Reed Papers (MSS Reed). Materials pertaining to August L. Strand and James A. Jensen are included in the Fred M. Shideler Papers (MSS Shideler).
President's Office publications (PUB 247) are also available in the Special Collections and Archives Research Center. Various files in the OSU Memorabilia Collection (MSS MC) also contain information on the OSU presidents.
Additional collections documenting the Oregon State Board/System of Higher Education include the Oregon State Board of Higher Education Records (RG 130), the Contract Administration Records (RG 212), the Oregon Higher Education Oral Histories Collection (OH 046), the Finance and Administration Records (RG 131), the Associated Students of Oregon State University (ASOSU) Records (RG 011), and the Registrar’s Office Records (RG053 - SG 1).
See also: The OSU Presidents Online Exhibit, featuring images and biographical sketches of OSU Presidents from 1865 to the present.
The President's Office General Subject and Correspondence Files are arranged in 3 series: 1. Organizations, 1940-1972; 2. Oregon State College / University, 1910-1974; and 3. Oregon State Board / System of Higher Education, 1940-1972.
The President's Office General Subject and Correspondence Files consist of microfilmed records documenting the administration and functioning of Oregon State University -- primarily during the 1950s and 1960s. These records were created and maintained by both the Presdient's Office and the Dean of Administration.
The records provide extensive documentation of the relationships with other colleges and universities, state and federal agences, and associations and organizations. Records documenting the instruction and research programs of the University, student life, institutional services and administration, and the financial functioning of the institution comprise Series 2.
The functioning of the Oregon State System of Higher Education and the Oregon State Board of Higher Education and Oregon State University's role in that system are documented in Series 3.
- Organizations, 1940-1972; Series 1
  Series 1 features 31 Sub-Series documenting the University’s and the President’s Office relationship with various organizations. Organizations include: the American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities; the National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges; the American Association of University Professors; the American Council of Education; the Northwest Association of Secondary and Higher Schools; the State of Oregon; the U.S. Government; the Western Interstate Commission of Higher Education; the Executive Committee; the Ford Foundation; and the National Science Foundation. Related subjects include: Colleges and Universities (e.g. Pacific Northwest Conference on the Arts and Sciences, Pacific Northwest Conference on Higher Education); Corvallis (e.g. Chambers of Commerce, College Fire Station); information, inquiries and requestions from or requested by various organizations; various groups related to communism; and departments (e.g. Pacific Power and Light, Ellis L. Phillips Foundation, The Oregonian).
  - "A" (Reel-folder 85.1)
  - Agency for International Development (Reel-folder 85.2)
  - "Am" (Reel-folder 85.3)
  - American Assembly Uses of the Sea, May 1969 (Reel-folder 85.4)
  - Overcoming World Hunger, September 1969 (Reel 85)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Reel-folder 85.5)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities
    - Centennial, 1962 (Reel-folder 85.6)
    - Executive Committee, 1966-1967 (Reel-folder 85.7)
    - Executive Committee, 1965 (Reel-folder 85.8)
    - Executive Secretary, 1956-1967 (Reel-folder 85.9)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges
    - General (1 of 3), 1968 (Reel-folder 85.10)
    - General (2 of 3), 1967-1968 (Reel-folder 85.11)
    - General (3 of 3), 1961-1967 (Reel-folder 85.12)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities
    - General (1 of 2), 1966 (Reel-folder 85.13)
    - General (2 of 2), 1966 (Reel-folder 85.14)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges
    - International Rural Development Office, 6/29/66-1/29/68 (Reel-folder 85.15)
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research, 10/1/67-5/31/68 (Reel-folder 85.16)
  - American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and Universities
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research (1 of 3), 12/1/66-9/30/67 (Reel-folder 85.17)
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research (2 of 3), 6/1/65-12/1/66 (Reel-folder 85.18)
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research (3 of 3), 7/1/60-6/15/67 (Reel-folder 85.19)
    - President's Council (Reel-folder 85.20)
    - Public Information Committee (Reel-folder 85.21)
  - American Association of University Professors
    - 1940-6/30/60 (Reel-folder 85.22)
    - 7/1/60-6/15/67 (Reel-folder 85.23)
  - American Council of Education
    - 8/1/67-6/31/68 (Reel-folder 85.24)
    - 9/1/65-7/31/67 (Reel-folder 85.25)
    - 1/1/64-8/31/65 (Reel-folder 85.26)
    - 7/1/61-12/31/63 (Reel-folder 85.27)
    - 7/1/60-7/1/61 (Reel-folder 85.28)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organization (Reel-folder 85.29)
  - American Red Cross (Reel-folder 85.30)
  - Association of Naval ROTC Colleges (Reel-folder 85.31)
  - "B" (Reel-folder 85.32)
  - "Be" (Reel-folder 85.33)
  - Benton County United Fund (Community Chest), 1945-1962 (Reel-folder 85.34)
  - "Bi" (Reel-folder 85.35)
  - "Bo" (Reel-folder 85.36)
  - "Br" (Reel-folder 85.37)
  - "Bro" (Reel-folder 85.38)
  - Brookings Institution, The (Reel-folder 85.39)
  - Capital Journal (Reel-folder 85.40)
  - "Car" (Reel-folder 85.41)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Reel-folder 85.42)
  - "Ch" (Reel-folder 85.43)
  - Charlton Laboratories, Inc. (Reel-folder 85.44)
  - "Co" (Reel-folder 85.45)
  - Colleges and Universities
    - Inaugurations - General, 6/1/69-12/31/70 (Reel-folder 85.46)
    - General (1 of 3), 6/16/67-4/30/68 (Reel-folder 85.47)
    - General (2 of 3), 5/1/68-12/31/70 (Reel-folder 85.47a)
    - General (3 of 3), 7/1/65-6/15/67 (Reel-folder 85.48)
  - Columbia Basin Inter-Agency Committee (Reel-folder 85.49)
  - Communism - General, 7/1/54 (Reel-folder 85.50)
  - Complaints - General (1 of 2), 7/31/67 (Reel-folder 85.51)
  - Complaints - General (2 of 2), 8/1/67 (Reel-folder 85.52)
  - "Con" (Reel-folder 85.53)
  - Coordinating Council for Higher Education (John R. Richards) (Reel-folder 85.54)
  - Corvallis
    - Chambers of Commerce, 6/31/60 (Reel-folder 85.55)
    - Chamber of Commerce - Industrial Development Division - New Industries Committee (Dr. Strand) (Reel-folder 85.56)
    - College Fire Station (proposed) (Reel-folder 85.57)
    - Conference on Research and Development for Oregon Small Business (Reel-folder 85.58)
    - Correspondence, 1944-6/30/60 (Reel-folder 85.59)
    - Paving Project (Reel-folder 85.60)
    - Test center for Air Traffic Control (Proposed at Corvallis Airport) (Reel-folder 85.61)
  - Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs, Inc. (Reel-folder 85.62)
    Contract to Finance Farm Management Program in Thailand
  - Danforth Foundation, 1940-6/30/60 (Reel-folder 85.63)
  - "Cr" (Reel-folder 85.64)
  - "De" (Reel-folder 85.65)
  - "Do" (Reel-folder 85.66)
  - "E" (Reel-folder 85.67)
  - "Ei" (Reel-folder 85.68)
  - Employee Suggestion Awards (Reel-folder 85.69)
  - Dean of Engineering Selection Committee (Reel-folder 85.70)
  - "F" (Reel-folder 85.71)
  - "Fi" (Reel-folder 85.72)
  - "Fr" (Reel-folder 85.73)
  - Fulbright-Exchange Scholars to OSC (Reel-folder 85.74)
  - "G" (Reel-folder 85.75)
  - "Gi" (Reel-folder 85.76)
  - "Gr" (Reel-folder 85.77)
  - Graduate Center at Portland State (1 of 2) (Reel-folder 85.78)
  - Graduate Center at Portland State (2 of 2) (Reel-folder 86.78)
  - "H" (Reel-folder 86.79)
  - "Har" (Reel-folder 86.80)
  - "He" (Reel-folder 86.81)
  - "Ho" (Reel-folder 86.82)
  - "Hu" (Reel-folder 86.83)
  - "I" (Reel-folder 86.84)
  - Information, Inquiries and Requests
    - 1969 thru 1971 (Reel-folder 86.85)
    - 1968 thru 1969 (Reel-folder 86.86)
    - 1967 thru 1968 (Reel-folder 86.87)
    - 1965 thru 1967 (Reel-folder 86.88)
    - 1964 (Reel-folder 86.89)
    - 1959 thru 1961 (Reel-folder 86.90)
    - 1956 thru 1959 (Reel-folder 86.91)
  - International Cooperation Administration - General Correspondence, 1957-1961 (Reel-folder 86.92)
  - "J" (Reel-folder 86.93)
  - "Jo" (Reel-folder 86.94)
  - "K" (Reel-folder 86.95)
  - "Ki" (Reel-folder 86.96)
  - "Ko" (Reel-folder 86.97)
  - "L" (Reel-folder 86.98)
  - Laws, Land-Grant Colleges (Reel-folder 86.99)
  - "Le" (Reel-folder 86.100)
  - "Li" (Reel-folder 86.101)
  - "Lo" (Reel-folder 86.102)
  - "M" (Reel-folder 86.103)
  - "Mar" (Reel-folder 86.104)
  - "Mc" (Reel-folder 86.105)
  - "Me" (Reel-folder 86.106)
  - "Mo" (Reel-folder 86.107)
  - "Mu" (Reel-folder 86.108)
  - "N" (Reel-folder 86.109)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges
    - General (1 of 2) (Reel-folder 86.110)
    - International Program Office (Rural Development), 1968-1970 (Reel-folder 86.111)
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research, 1968-1969 (Reel-folder 86.112)
    - General (2 of 2), 1968 (Reel-folder 86.113)
  - National Commission on Accrediting, 1956-1967 (Reel-folder 86.114)
  - National Economic Council, 1949 (Reel-folder 86.115)
  - National Grange (Reel-folder 86.116)
  - National - Correspondence File A-Z, 1960-1966 (Reel-folder 86.117)
  - National Project in Agricultural Communication (Reel-folder 86.118)
    Financed by the Kellogg Foundation
  - National Science Foundation (1 of 2), 1963-1966 (Map-folder 86.119)
  - National Science Foundation (2 of 2), 1966-1970 (Reel-folder 86.120)
  - "Ni" (Reel-folder 86.121)
  - Northwest Association of Secondary and Higher Schools
    - 1954 thru 1968 (Reel-folder 86.122)
    - Accreditation (Reel-folder 86.123)
  - Northwest Hospital (Blue Cross) Service (Reel-folder 86.124)
  - "O" (Reel-folder 86.125)
  - Oregon Association of State Fiscal and Administrative Officers, 1967 (Reel-folder 86.126)
  - Oregon Bankers Association - Agricultural Clinic (Reel-folder 86.127)
  - Oregon Farm Bureau (Reel-folder 86.128)
  - Oregon Farmer (Reel-folder 86.129)
  - Oregon Farmers Union (Oregon, Washington Farmers) (Reel-folder 86.130)
  - Oregon Forest Research Center (Reel-folder 86.131)
  - Oregon Historical Society (Reel-folder 86.132)
  - Oregon Livestock Feed Conservation Committee (Reel-folder 86.133)
  - Oregon Physicians Service (Reel-folder 86.134)
  - Oregon Regional Primate Research Center (Reel-folder 86.135)
  - Oregon Research Associates, Inc. (Reel-folder 86.136)
  - Oregon, State of
    Reel-Folder numbers starting with 1 added during data entry, as no numbers were assigned in container list.
    - Boards and Commissions (Reel-folder 1.01)
    - Departments (Reel-folder 1.02)
    - Employees Association (1 of 2), 1967-1970 (Reel-folder 86.155)
    - Employees Association (2 of 2), 1958-1967 (Reel-folder 86.156)
    - Legislation (Reel-folder 1.03)
  - Oregon State System of Higher Education - Statistics - Enrollments (Reel-folder 87.164)
  - OSU - Instructional Service - Registrar Enrollments, 1965-1969 (Reel-folder 87.165)
  - OSC Reference File - School of Agriculture Publications Outline Series (Reel-folder 87.166)
  - OSU Staff - Organizations - American Association of University Professors, 1965-1969 (Reel-folder 87.167)
  - Oregon State College - Reference File, Student Life and Welfare Foreign Students (Reel-folder 87.168)
  - Oregon Wheat Growers - League Commission (Reel-folder 87.169)
  - Pacific Northwest Trade Association (Reel-folder 87.170)
  - "Pa" (Reel-folder 87.171)
  - "Pe" (Reel-folder 87.172)
  - "Pi" (Reel-folder 87.173)
  - "Pr" (Reel-folder 87.174)
  - Pacific Northwest Development Association (Reel-folder 87.175)
  - "R" (Reel-folder 87.176)
  - "Ri" (Reel-folder 87.177)
  - "Ro" (Reel-folder 87.178)
  - "Ros" (Reel-folder 87.179)
  - "S" (Reel-folder 87.180)
  - "Sc" (Reel-folder 87.181)
  - School of Administrators - Conference, Salem, 1944 (Reel-folder 87.182)
    Took place from October 9th thru 11th
  - "Se" (Reel-folder 87.183)
  - "Si" (Reel-folder 87.184)
  - "Sm" (Reel-folder 87.185)
  - "Sn" (Reel-folder 87.186)
  - Speech Material - President A.L. Strand, Activities at OSC (Reel-folder 87.187)
  - Speech Material - Historical Data - OSC - President A.L. Strand (Reel-folder 87.188)
  - Speech Material - Data (Reel-folder 87.189)
  - Speeches, Statements, etc. - President A.L. Strand (Reel-folder 87.190)
  - "St" (Reel-folder 87.191)
  - Staff Statistics (Reel-folder 87.192)
  - Stanford Research Institute (Reel-folder 87.193)
  - "Su" (Reel-folder 87.194)
  - "T" (Reel-folder 87.195)
  - "To" (Reel-folder 87.196)
  - "U" (Reel-folder 87.197)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce (Reel-folder 87.198)
  - U.S. Government
    - Federal Communications Commission (Reel-folder 87.199)
    - Departments (Reel-folder 1.01)
    - General - Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, 1966-1967 (Reel-folder 87.208)
    - Legislation (Reel-folder 1.02)
  - "V" (Reel-folder 87.212)
  - "W" (Reel-folder 87.213)
  - "W" (Reel-folder 87.214)
  - Western Interstate Commission of Higher Education
    - 1967 thru 1970 (Reel-folder 87.215)
    - 1960 thru 1967 (Reel-folder 87.216)
  - "Wh" (Reel-folder 87.217)
  - "Wi" (Reel-folder 87.218)
  - "Wo" (Reel-folder 87.219)
  - "XYZ" (Reel-folder 87.220)
  - "A" (Reel-folder 114.1)
  - "Al" (Reel-folder 114.2)
  - "Am" (Reel-folder 114.3)
  - "Ar" (Reel-folder 114.4)
  - Advisory Board on Conservation Problems, 1947-1951 (Reel-folder 114.5)
  - Alaskan Science Conference, 1951 (Reel-folder 114.6)
  - American Academy of Asian Studies - Graduate School, 1952 (Reel-folder 114.7)
  - American Association of Collegiate Registrars (Reel-folder 114.8)
  - American Association of University Professors (Reel-folder 114.9)
  - American College Public Relations Association (Reel-folder 114.10)
  - American Council on Education
    - 1958 thru 1971 (Reel-folder 114.11)
    - Office of Institutional Projects Abroad, 1954-1958 (Reel-folder 114.13)
    - Pharmaceutical Survey, 1947-1950 (Reel-folder 114.14)
    - Rykukyus-University Cooperative Relationship, 1951 (Reel-folder 114.15)
    - American Council of Pharmaceutical Education (Reel-folder 114.16)
  - American Osteopathic Association (Reel-folder 114.17)
  - American Society for Engineering Education, 1955-1960 (Reel-folder 114.18)
  - Associated Forest Industries of Oregon (Reel-folder 114.19)
  - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities, 1947-1957 (Reel-folder 114.21)
  - Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges
    - Committee on Agricultural and General Extension Study (Reel-folder 114.32)
    - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations (Reel-folder 114.33)
    - Committee on Unjustifiable Controls of Public Colleges and Universities (Reel-folder 114.34)
    - Committee of Necrology (Reel-folder 114.35)
    - Committee on Financing Publications of Research Findings (Reel-folder 114.36)
    - Committee on Training for Government Service, 1944-1950 (Reel-folder 114.37)
  - Executive Committee
    - Executive Secretary, 1950-1956 (Reel-folder 114.45)
    - General (1 of 5), 1959-1960 (Reel-folder 114.46)
    - General (2 of 5), 1960-1961 (Reel-folder 114.47)
    - General (3 of 5), 1960-1961 (Reel-folder 115.47)
    - General (4 of 5), 1961-1965 (Reel-folder 115.48)
    - General (5 of 5), 1961-1965 (Reel-folder 115.49)
    - Joint Office of Institutional Research, 1958-1960 (Reel-folder 115.50)
  - Association of Naval ROTC Colleges (Reel-folder 115.51)
  - Benton County Tuberculosis Association (Reel-folder 115.52)
  - Benton County - Huffaker Report (Reel-folder 115.52a)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (Reel-folder 115.53)
  - China Institute in America (Reel-folder 115.54)
  - Colleges and Universities
    - Northwest Personnel Conference, 1947 (Reel-folder 115.56)
    - Northwest Regional Hazen Conference, 1946 (Reel-folder 115.57)
    - Pacific Northwest College Congress (Reel-folder 115.58)
    - Pacific Northwest Committee of Human Relations in Higher Education (Reel-folder 115.59)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on the Arts and Sciences (1 of 2) (Reel-folder 115.60)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on the Arts and Sciences (2 of 2) (Reel-folder 115.61)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on Higher Education (1 of 4), 1946-1952 (Reel-folder 115.62)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on Higher Education (2 of 4), 1946-1952 (Reel-folder 115.63)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on Higher Education (3 of 4), 1946-1952 (Reel-folder 115.64)
    - Pacific Northwest Conference on Higher Education (4 of 4), 1946-1952 (Reel-folder 115.65)
    - University of California at Los Angeles - Western Data Processing Center (Dean Maser) (Reel-folder 115.66)
    - University of Washington, 1952-1960 (Reel-folder 115.68)
    - Washington State College (Reel-folder 115.69)
    - Inaugurations, 1961-1962 (Reel-folder 115.73)
    - General, 1959-1965 (Reel-folder 115.75-79a)
  - Columbia Basin Area - Comprehensive Agricultural Program (Reel-folder 115.80)
  - Columbia Valley Authority (Reel-folder 115.84)
  - Communism
    - Magruder Book (Reel-folder 115.87)
    - Social Science - Publications (Reel-folder 115.88)
    - General, 1949-1954 (Reel-folder 115.89)
  - Corvallis
    - Centennial, 1857-1957 (Reel-folder 115.92)
    - Chamber of Commerce - Military Affairs Committee (Dean Lemon) (Reel-folder 115.93)
    - Eugene - Utilities (Reel-folder 115.94)
    - Street Light Project (Reel-folder 115.95)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc. (Reel-folder 115.96)
  - Fairbanks, Dr. Avard, 1946-1955 (Reel-folder 115.97)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Faculty Fellowships, 1951-1956 (Reel-folder 115.98)
    - General, 1951-1956 (Reel-folder 115.99)
  - Hall, Gus - Communist Speaker, 1962 (Reel-folder 115.101)
  - Harris, Donald W. (accident claim) (Reel-folder 115.102)
  - Industrial College of Armed Forces (Reel-folder 115.103)
  - Institute of International Education, 1944-1960 (Reel-folder 115.104-105)
  - Jefferson County Submarginal Land (Reel-folder 115.108)
  - Korean Institute Committee (Charles W. Edmunds, M.D.) (Reel-folder 115.113)
  - Land Problems Research Center (Reel-folder 115.114)
  - Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory Conference, 1946 (Reel-folder 115.115)
  - "N" Correspondence (Reel-folder 115.116)
  - National Association of Science Teachers (Science Talent Search) (Reel-folder 115.120)
  - National Athletic Association, 1945-1966 (Reel-folder 115.121-124)
  - National Commission of Accrediting, 1950-1956 (Reel-folder 115.125-126)
  - National Education Association, 1949-1960 (Reel-folder 115.127-129)
  - National Institute for Traffic Training (Reel-folder 115.130)
  - National Interfraternity Conference (Reel-folder 115.131)
  - National Science Foundation
    - General (1 of 2), 1959-1962 (Reel-folder 115.133)
    - General (2 of 2), 1959-1962 (Reel-folder 115.134)
    - Survey of Expenditures on Research and Development at Universities and Colleges - Forms 883 and 884 (Reel-folder 115.135)
    - General, 1946-1959 (Reel-folder 115.136)
  - National Student Association (Reel-folder 115.137)
  - Northwest Regional Committee (Reel-folder 115.142)
  - Northwest Regional Council - Correspondence and Final Report, 1941-1944 (Reel-folder 115.178)
  - Oregon
    - Academy of Science (Reel-folder 115.144)